### Mark Kille

5908 SW Illinois Street Portland, OR 97221 503-926-4816 markakille@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Information professional with 12 years of administrative experience including scheduling, publicity, supervision, customer relations and bookkeeping.

### **WORK SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE**

Microsoft Word (20 years).

Website administration and content creation (16 years).

Technology skills training (16 years).

Microsoft Excel and Publisher (13 years).

Planning and implementing cultural and educational programs (12 years).

Assessing organizational staffing needs (12 years).

Creating job descriptions and job postings (12 years).

Determining appropriate compensation for positions (12 years).

Reviewing candidate applications and conducting interviews (12 years).

On-boarding of new hires (12 years).

Ensuring compliance with federal and state labor laws (12 years).

Evaluating employee performance (12 years).

Tracking employee work time and paid leave (12 years).

Resolving conflicts within and between organizational levels (12 years).

Selecting and managing benefit plans (8.5 years).

Helping employees build long-term career plans (8.5 years).

Webserver administration (8 years).

Developing employee policies and procedures (7.5 years).

Microsoft PowerPoint (7 years).

QuickBooks (4 years).

Processing payroll (4 years).

Mentoring other supervisors (4 years).

GIMP and Adobe image management software (4 years).

## **WORK HISTORY**

Director, **Naropa University Library and Archives** (Boulder, CO), February 2007 - present Promoted from interim to permanent status in June 2009 in recognition of achievement.

Interim Director, Berthoud Public Library (Berthoud, CO), September 2006 - February 2007

Director, John P. Webster Library (West Hartford, CT), June 2003 - June 2006

Director, **Lilly Library** (Florence, MA), June 1999 - May 2003

Promoted from acting to permanent status in August 1999 in recognition of achievement.

### LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

Intermediate Spanish conversation and reading.

# **EDUCATION**

**Master of Theological Studies**, Iliff School of Theology, August 2011 (Expected)
All requirements completed. Thesis: "Taking Christian Education Public: Dialogue, Hospitality and Discernment."

Master of Library and Information Science, University of Pittsburgh, August 1998

**A.B., Linguistics with Celtic Languages and Literatures**, Harvard University, June 1995 Summa Cum Laude. Awarded Thomas Temple Hoopes Prize for Excellence in Undergraduate Writing.